seabird.com 2018-06-01

# Privacy Statement | Sea-Bird Scientific

## Online Privacy Policy

**WE UPDATED OUR PRIVACY NOTICE EFFECTIVE May 15, 2018.**

This Online Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") explains how Sea-Bird Scientific ("Sea-Bird") handles Personal Data provided to us on websites, mobile sites, mobile applications, and other digital services/products controlled by Sea-Bird that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, "Sea-Bird Sites").  Sea-Bird is the data controller for the processing of Personal Data under applicable law.

This Privacy Notice does not apply to Sea-Bird Sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy or to third-party websites linked from Sea-Bird Sites.

**Summary**  
This summary section provides a brief overview of our Privacy Notice. Please read the full Privacy Policy below for more detailed information.

  * Information We Collect
  * How We Use Your Information
  * Information We Share
  * Your Privacy Choices
  * Security
  * Accessing Our Sites Globally
  * Changes to Our Privacy Notice

**Information We Collect**  
Sea-Bird collects the following types of information through the Sea-Bird Site(s):

  * Information you provide. Personal Data you provide when registering for our products and services, responding to questionnaires, surveys, or contacting Sea-Bird customer service.
  * Information collected automatically. Your IP address and non-identifying information about your use of Sea-Bird Sites may be collected automatically using tracking technologies, such as cookies. Your website browser software can be set to reject all cookies; however, cookies can allow you to take advantage of some of the site's essential features, which may not work if you reject cookies.
  * Information collected from other sources. We may combine information about you from Sea-Bird Sites, information collected offline or from external parties.

**How We Use Your Information**  
Sea-Bird uses the information we collect for several purposes, mainly:

  * To provide you with the Sea-Bird products and services you request.
  * To offer and provide information about similar and/or related products and services.
  * To customize and improve your experience on Sea-Bird Sites.
  * To generally improve our products and Sea-Bird Sites and other internal business purposes.
  * Legal obligations to notify and report to authorities.

Under European data protection laws, Sea-Bird must have a legal basis to process your Personal Data. The legal basis that applies in an instance will depend on which of the specific purposes described above are processing your Personal Data:

  * In certain cases, Danaher may ask for your consent to collect and process your Personal Data. Should you choose to provide your consent, you may later withdraw your consent by contacting us as described in the "Your Privacy Choices" section. Please note that the withdrawal of consent will not affect processing which has already occurred.
  * In other instances, the processing of your Personal Data may be necessary in order to comply with an applicable law or regulation or for the performance of a contract to which you are subject. You may not be able to opt-out of this processing, or your choice to opt-out may impact our ability to perform a contractual obligation otherwise owed to you.
  * In still other instances, Sea-Bird may process your Personal Data based on Sea-Bird's legitimate interests in communicating with you about our products and services, and about scientific research and educational opportunities. You have the right to opt-out of all such processing of your Personal Data. You may do so by contacting us as described in the "Your Privacy Choices" section.

Processing operations may include the recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction of Personal Data. The Personal Data we collect about you may be stored for five years following the most recent interaction we have had with you, after which point it will be archived only for so long as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out above, in accordance with applicable laws.

**Information We Share**  
Sea-Bird does not sell or disclose your personal information to unrelated third parties without your consent, except:

  * To affiliates and third-party service providers to provide services and information on our sites, including online marketing and advertising, and to support our business operations. We require these parties to handle Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Notice.
  * To affiliates to offer and provide information about related products and services. We do not share Personal Data from countries that require consent, unless consent has been obtained in advance for sharing with related affiliates. We require these parties to handle Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Notice.
  * To another company in connection with the sale or transfer of one of our product lines or divisions, which includes the services provided through one or more of Sea-Bird's affiliates.
  * To governing regulatory authorities, including the US Food and Drug Administration, or as may otherwise be necessary for Sea-Bird to comply with a legal obligation or demand.
  * In the event Sea-Bird decides to reorganize or divest our business through sale, merger, or acquisition, Sea-Bird may share Personal Data about you with actual or prospective purchasers. We will require any actual or prospective purchasers to treat this Personal Data in a manner consistent with this notice.
  * You can find all related affiliates on our International Affiliates page under Sales/Service in the menu.

**Your Privacy Choices**

You have the right to see and get a copy of your Personal Data that we maintain as well as to ask us to make corrections to inaccurate or incomplete Personal Data about you. You have the right to receive data you have provided to us in a machine-readable format and to transmit that data to another controller. You may also request the erasure of your Personal Data or the restriction of its processing, or object to the processing of Personal Data about you. To seek access to Personal Data about you, to file a concern, complaint, or request for correction, or to opt-out of particular programs, please contact our Privacy Leader by clicking on the "Ask Us" link on the Sea-Bird Site you are using, or by emailing us at [news@seabird.com](mailto:news@seabird.com). You may also send a letter to the following address:

**Sea-Bird Scientific  
Attn: Privacy**  
13431 NE 20th Street,  
Bellevue, Washington  
98005  USA

Your country's Data Protection Authority is responsible for making sure that privacy law is followed your country. For more information about your privacy rights, or if you are not able to resolve a problem directly with us and wish to make a compliant, contact your country's Data Protection Authority.

**Security**  
Sea-Bird maintains controls to protect and secure Personal Data, but when you share Personal Data online there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party could gain access to your information.

**Accessing Our Sites Globally**  
By using this site, you understand that your Personal Data will be collected, stored, and processed in the United States and in any country to which we may transfer your information in the course of our business operations. Sea-Bird may transmit Personal Data about you to related affiliates worldwide. These affiliates may in turn transmit Personal Data about you to other related affiliates. Some affiliates may be in countries that do not ensure an adequate level of data protection. Nevertheless, all of our related affiliates are required to treat Personal Data in a manner consistent with this notice. To obtain additional information regarding the safeguards we have in place for cross-border transfers of Personal Data, please contact us using the information provided in the "Your Privacy Choices" section.

**Changes to Our Privacy Notice**  
Check this Privacy Notice regularly, as we may change or update portions of this Privacy Policy from time to time, subject to any applicable consent requirements. Any changes will be promptly posted to this page and accompanied by a new effective date at the top of this page.

## **Privacy Policy** Effective April 21, 2017

This Online Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains how Sea-Bird Scientific (" **Sea-Bird** ") handles personal information provided to us on websites, mobile sites, mobile applications, and other digital services and products controlled by Sea-Bird that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, “ **Sea-Bird Sites** ”).

This Privacy Notice does not apply to Sea-Bird Sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy or to third-party websites linked from Sea-Bird Sites.

**Summary**  
This summary section provides a brief overview of our Privacy Notice. Please read the full Privacy Policy below for more detailed information.

  * Information We Collect
  * How We Use Your Information
  * Information We Share
  * Your Privacy Choices
  * Security
  * Accessing Our Sites Globally
  * Changes to Our Privacy Notice

**Information We Collect**  
Sea-Bird collects the following types of information through the Sea-Bird Site(s):

  * **Information you provide. Personal Information** you provide when registering for our products and services, responding to questionnaires or surveys, or contacting Sea-Bird customer service.
  * **Information collected automatically.**  Your IP address and non-identifying information about your use of Sea-Bird Sites may be collected automatically using tracking technologies, such as cookies. Your website browser software can be set to reject all cookies; however, cookies can allow you to take advantage of some of the site’s essential features, which may not work if you reject cookies.
  * **Information collected from other sources.**  We may combine information about you from Sea-Bird Sites, information collected offline or from external parties.

**How We Use Your Information**  
Sea-Bird uses the information we collect for several purposes, mainly:

  * To provide you with the Sea-Bird product and services you request.
  * To customize and improve your experience on Sea-Bird Site(s).
  * To generally improve our products and Sea-Bird Site(s) and other internal business purposes.

**Information We Share**  
Sea-Bird does not sell or disclose your personal information to unrelated third parties without your consent, except:

  * To affiliates and third-party service providers to provide services and information on our sites, including online marketing and advertising, and to support our business operations. We require these parties to handle personal information in accordance with this Privacy Notice.
  * To another company in connection with the sale or transfer of one of our product lines or divisions, which includes the services provided through this site.
  * To governing regulatory authorities, including the US Food and Drug Administration, or as may otherwise be necessary for Sea-Bird to comply with a legal obligation or demand.

**Your Privacy Choices**  
If you have questions about this Privacy Notice, if you want to change your personal information, or if you would like to opt-out of a Sea-Bird online program, please contact us by clicking on the “Ask Us” link on this site, or by emailing us at [news@seabird.com](mailto:news@seabird.com). You may also send a letter to the following address:

Sea-Bird Scientific  
Attn: Privacy  
13431 NE 20th Street,  
Bellevue, Washington  
98005  USA

**Security**  
Sea-Bird maintains controls to protect and secure personal information, but when you share personal information online there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party could gain access to your information.

**Accessing Our Sites Globally**  
By using this site, you consent to the collection, storage, and processing of your information in the United States and in any country to which we may transfer your information in the course of our business operations.

**Changes to Our Privacy Notice**  
Check this Privacy Notice regularly, as we may change or update portions of this Privacy Policy from time to time, subject to any applicable consent requirements. Any changes will be promptly posted to this page and accompanied by a new effective date at the top of this page.

## **Privacy Policy** **Effective June 15, 2015**

This Online Privacy Notice (“Privacy Policy”) explains how we handle the personal information provided to us on websites, mobile sites, mobile applications, and other digital services and products controlled by Sea-Bird Scientific, 13431 NE 20th Street, Bellevue, Washington 98005  USA, that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, “Sea-Bird Sites”). This Privacy Notice does not apply to Sea-Bird Sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy or to third-party Web sites to which Sea-Bird Sites may link.

**_Types of Information We Collect Online_**  
The types of personal information that we may collect while you use the Sea-Bird Sites are described in this section and include both information that you provide to us and information that we collect automatically when you use the Sea-Bird Sites.  
For purposes of this Privacy Notice, “ **Personal Information** ” means information that identifies you or that could reasonably be used to identify you. Examples of Personal Information include name, address, telephone number, and email address.

**_Information You Provide_**  
You do not have to register for a service or program to receive much of the information available through Sea-Bird Sites. However, some of our content is available only to registered or identified users and will require you to set up a profile or provide specific information about yourself in order to provide you the service.

> **Personal Information You Provide When Visiting Sea-Bird Sites**  
>  Sea-Bird collects Personal Information that you provide on Sea-Bird Sites, for example, when purchasing a product, to receive marketing products and information, contact Sea-Bird customer service, or respond to Sea-Bird questionnaires or surveys. This could include:
> 
>   * Contact Information such as your name, address, phone number, or email address
>   * Registration Information such as your username and password
>   * Employment, education and other background information when you inquire about employment with Sea-Bird
>   * Payment information (such as banking information, payment card number, expiration date, delivery address, and billing address)
>   * Content you may provide (for example, when you complete our Online Contact Form or submit other information).
> 

> 
> **Personal Information You Share During Other Interactions with Sea-Bird**  
>  You may contact Sea-Bird to ask questions, discuss your concerns, or report issues regarding our products. If you communicate with or request information from Sea-Bird, you may be prompted to provide your contact information as well as any personal information that is relevant to your request.

**_Information That May Be Collected Automatically_** __  
When you use the Sea-Bird Sites, we also may collect certain usage and device information automatically as described below.

> **IP Address**  
>  We may record the Internet Protocol (“IP”) address of your computer or other electronic device when you visit the Sea-Bird Sites. An IP address identifies the electronic device you use to access the Sites, which allows us to maintain communication with your computer as you move about Sea-Bird Sites and to customize content.
> 
> **Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**  
>  We also collect information about your use of Sea-Bird Sites through tracking technologies such as cookies and web beacons. A “cookie” is a unique numeric code that is transferred to your computer to track your interests and preferences and to recognize you as a return visitor. A “Web beacon” is a transparent graphic image placed on a Web site, e-mail or advertisement that enables the monitoring of things such as user activity and site traffic. These technologies help remember your preferences and allow us to bring you the content and features that are likely to be of greatest interest to you on the basis of “clickstream” data that shows your previous activities on Sea-Bird Sites.
> 
> We utilize Google Display Advertising (such as Retargeting with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting) to (1) show you our ads on other websites based on your prior visits to Sea-Bird Sites, and (2) better understand our ad impressions and use of ad services. In connection with the Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting service, we may use data from Google's interest-based advertising or third-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) with Google Analytics to understand and improve our marketing campaigns and Site content.
> 
> Some of our online advertising takes place through Google Display Advertising. As part of this program, we use Google Analytics features such as Retargeting. In connection with that feature and others offered by ad networks, we and the operators of ad networks, including Google, may use third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) – and in some cases first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) – to inform, optimize and serve ads across the Internet, based on a user's past visits to Sea-Bird Sites.
> 
> You can opt out of Google Ads by visiting <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences>. If you do not want your data used by Google Analytics, you can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on at the [Google Analytics opt-out page](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
> 
> This Sea-Bird Site is not designed to respond to "do not track" signals received from browsers.  
>  To learn more about cookies and other tracking technologies, including how to disable them, please visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. Please note that some cookies are essential to the functioning of our Sites and deleting or disabling them will reduce the site’s functionality.
> 
> **Information Collected from Other Sources**  
>  We may combine information about you from a visit to one Sea-Bird Site with information about you from visits to other Sea-Bird Sites. We may also combine information about you that is collected through the Sea-Bird Sites with information that we have collected offline, as well as with information provided to us by third parties.

**_How We Use Your Information_**  
We use your Personal Information to provide you the product and services you request, communicate with you, improve your experience on the Sea-Bird Sites, generally improve our products and services and for other internal business purposes, as described in more detail below.

> **Providing Product and Services You Request**  
>  If you choose to purchase a product or receive our services, we use the Personal Information that you provide through Sea-Bird Sites to manage your orders and invoices, to process payments, to respond to your questions, provide you the services you request and offer an optimal customer experience.
> 
> **Marketing**  
>  You may also choose to receive marketing information from Sea-Bird, such as offers regarding Sea-Bird’s products or services, invitations to participate in surveys about our products, or notifications about special promotions. In such cases, we will use your contact and other Personal Information to send you marketing information.
> 
> **Customized User Experiences**  
>  The Personal Information that you provide may be used to create customized offers, information, or services tailored to your interests and preferences. Also, we may use your IP address and the data that we obtain automatically through the use of cookies or similar tracking technologies to make our Sea-Bird Sites easier to use and navigate as well as to personalize the content provided on Sea-Bird Sites by anticipating the information and services that may be of interest to you.
> 
> **Business and Product Improvement**  
>  In order to discover new facts that could help Sea-Bird better understand customer needs and help improve, develop, and evaluate product, services, materials, and programs. Sea-Bird analyzes the information that you have provided. For these purposes Sea-Bird does not use information that can directly identify you.
> 
> **Site Analytics and Improvement**  
>  We may use the information that you provide and the information we collect automatically about your use of the Sea-Bird Sites to monitor user traffic patterns and preferences for site improvement, analytics and optimization.

**_Information We Share_**  
We only share your Personal Information with third parties as described below. We do not sell or rent Personal Information to third parties for their own marketing purposes.

> **Third-Party Advertising and Online Behavioral Advertising**  
>  You may be provided with online advertisements of Sea-Bird products and services on third-party websites and mobile services that are tailored to you, for example, on the basis of information that you provide to Sea-Bird or a third-party website you are visiting, or of your browsing activity, purchases, or interests. These types of tailored online advertisements may come through several sources, such as the following:
> 
>   * We may share with our advertising service providers your non-identifying information that we have obtained from cookies and other tracking technologies on our Sea-Bird Sites.
>   * Some Sea-Bird Sites participate in online behavioral advertising (this is also sometimes called re-target advertising or interest-based advertising). You can identify these sites by the “Advertising Choices” link in the footer. Our advertising network partners may place and use cookies on Sea-Bird Web sites and on other third-party Web sites to collect information about your activities in order to provide you with online advertisements that are based on your interests. When a Sea-Bird online behavioral advertisement is delivered to you, you will see an “Ad Choices” icon. Clicking on the icon or link will take you to a Web site where you can manage or opt out of the use of data about your browsing history that is used for the delivery of online behavioral advertisements. If you opt out, you may still see advertisements online, including advertisements from Sea-Bird that are based on other information (e.g., based on the content of the page being viewed rather than your prior clickstream activity). In some cases, data may still be collected about your browsing activity by these third-party advertisers, but they will not use this data to deliver advertisements that are based on your past online browsing behavior. You can also opt out now by clicking [here](https://info.evidon.com/pub_info/6678?v=1&nt=0&nw=true).
>   * Some Web browsers may transmit “do-not-track” signals to Web sites with which the browser communicates. As of the Effective Date of this Privacy Notice, an industry standard has not yet been established on how to respond to these signals. Therefore, Sea-Bird does not currently respond to these signals. As discussed above, you can opt-out from advertisers that use your browsing history to deliver online behavioral advertisements by visiting [adchoices](https://info.evidon.com/pub_info/6678?v=1&nt=0&nw=true).
> 

> 
> **Affiliates, Vendors and Suppliers**  
>  We have relationships with various vendors and suppliers, including our affiliated companies, who help us operate our business and for whom it may be necessary to have access to your Personal Information in the course of providing services to Sea-Bird. We will not authorize these parties to use your Personal Information for any purpose that is not related to Sea-Bird’s business operation, and we require them to handle your Personal Information collected through the Sea-Bird Sites in accordance with this Privacy Notice.
> 
> **Co-branded Sites**  
>  We may partner with other companies to provide you with content or services on a joint or “co-branded” basis. At a co‑branded site, you will see both the Sea-Bird logo and the logo of the co-branding partner displayed on your screen. You should read the individual privacy policies of our co-branding partners, as they may differ in some respects from ours. Reading these policies will help you to make an informed decision about whether to provide your information to a given site.
> 
> **Product Reports**  
>  If you contact Sea-Bird regarding your experience in using one of our products, we may use the information that you provide in submitting reports to the designated government regulatory authority, such as the US Food and Drug Administration and as otherwise required of us by law.
> 
> **Legal Rights and Obligations**  
>  In certain limited circumstances, Sea-Bird may need to disclose your Personal Information in order to comply with a legal obligation or demand, such as to comply with reporting obligations to our governing regulatory authorities regarding the safety of our products, or in connection with the sale or transfer of one of our product lines or divisions, which includes the services provided through one or more of the Sea-Bird Sites. In such instances, we will take measures to protect your Personal Information to the extent possible. We also reserve the right to use Personal Information to investigate and prosecute users who violate our rules or who engage in behavior that is illegal or harmful to others or to others’ property.
> 
> **Children Privacy**  
>  Sea-Bird does not knowingly collect or use any personal information directly from children (we define “children” as minors younger than 13) on Sea-Bird Sites. We do not knowingly allow children to order our products, to communicate with us, or to use any of our online services. If you are a parent and become aware that your child has provided us with information, please contact us using one of the methods specified below, and we will work with you to address this issue.

**_Your Privacy Choices_**  
You may contact us at any time if you have questions about this Privacy Notice or the Personal Information we collect about you. You can also opt-out or unsubscribe from any of our services.

Please contact us by emailing us at [news@seabird.com](mailto:news@seabird.com). Alternatively, you may send a letter to the following address:

Sea-Bird Scientific  
Attn: Privacy  
13431 NE 20th Street,  
Bellevue, Washington  
98005  USA

In all communications to Sea-Bird, please include your email address, the Web site address, and/or the specific Sea-Bird product to which you provided Personal Information ( _e.g._ , seabird.com), and a detailed explanation of your request. If you would like to delete, amend, or correct your Personal Information and are contacting us by email, please put “Deletion Request” or “Amendment/Correction Request” in the subject line of the email. We will respond to all reasonable requests in a timely manner and may need to further confirm your identity in order to process certain requests.

**_Data Security_**  
Sea-Bird maintains reasonable technical, administrative and physical controls to secure any Personal Information collected through the Sea-Bird Sites. However, there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party could intercept an Internet transmission, or that someone will find a way to thwart our security systems. We urge you to exercise caution when transmitting Personal Information over the Internet, especially your financial-related information. Sea-Bird cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not gain access to your Personal Information; therefore, when submitting Personal Information to Sea-Bird Sites, you must weigh both the benefits and the risks.

**_Third Party Sites and Social Media Plug-ins_**  
This Privacy Notice does not apply to Sea-Bird Sites that do not link to this Privacy Notice, or to third-party Web sites to which Sea-Bird Sites may link. Sea-Bird Sites may use social media plug-ins (e.g., the Facebook “Like” button, “Share to Twitter” button) to enable you to easily share information with others. When you visit Sea-Bird Sites, the operator of the social plug-in can place a cookie on your computer or other electronic device that enables that operator to recognize individuals who have previously visited our Site. If you are logged into the social media Web site (e.g., Facebook, Twitter) while browsing on our Sea-Bird Site, the social media plug-in allows that social media Web site to receive information that you have visited our Sea-Bird Site. The social media plug-in also allows the social media Web site to share information about your activities on our Sea-Bird Site with other users of their social media Web site. These sharing settings are managed by the social media Web site and governed by its privacy policy.

> **Accessing Our Sites Globally**  
>  This site is owned and operated by Sea-Bird in the United States, but the information you provide will be accessible to our affiliates, vendors, and suppliers in other countries. Furthermore, if you are visiting this site from a country other than the United States, your communication with us will necessarily result in the transfer of information across international borders. The level of legal protection for personal information is not the same in all countries; however, we will take the security measures described in this Privacy Notice in an effort to keep your information secure. By using this site, you consent to the collection, storage, and processing of your information in the United States and in any country to which we may transfer your information in the course of our business operations.
> 
> **Notice to California Residents**  
>  Subject to certain limits under California Civil Code § 1798.83, California residents may ask us to provide them with (i) a list of certain categories of personal information that we have disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, and (ii) the identity of those third parties. To make this request, California residents may contact us at [news@seabird.com](mailto:news@seabird.com)

**_Changes to Our Privacy Policy_**  
We will only use Personal Information in the manner described in this Privacy Policy in effect when the information was collected from you or as authorized by you. However, and subject to any applicable consent requirements, we reserve the right to change the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be reflected on this page with a new effective date. Sea-Bird encourages you to review this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes. Any Personal Information collected upon your continued use of Sea-Bird Sites will be handled in accordance with the currently-posted Privacy Policy.

**Additional Language for Online Terms of Use**

## Privacy and Security

Sea-Bird Scientific, along with its affiliates and subsidiaries respect your privacy, value our relationship, and are committed to safeguarding your privacy. We understand the importance of privacy to our customers and visitors to the Sea-Bird websites. Our use of personally identifiable information is governed by our Privacy Policy and by accessing and using the Sea-Bird websites, you agree to be bound by that Privacy Policy.

You recognize and agree that when submitting your personally identifiable information to Sea-Bird websites, while Sea-Bird has safeguards in place to prevent unauthorized access or interception, there is no absolute guarantee of security. IN THE UNLIKELY EVENT OF AN INTERCEPTION OR UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS DESPITE OUR EFFORTS, Sea-Bird SHALL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE FOR SUCH INTERCEPTIONS OR UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS, OR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING LOST PROFITS) SUFFERED BY A CUSTOMER OR USER, EVEN IF Sea-Bird HAS PREVIOUSLY BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES, Sea-Bird DOES NOT WARRANT, EITHER EXPRESSLY OR IMPLIED, THAT THE INFORMATION PROVIDED BY ANY CUSTOMER SHALL BE FREE FROM INTERCEPTION OR UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS, AND DOES NOT PROVIDE ANY IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. EACH CUSTOMER IS RESPONSIBLE FOR MAINTAINING THE CONFIDENTIALITY OF HIS OR HER OWN PASSWORD.

This Online Privacy Notice ("Privacy Policy") explains how we handle the Personal Data provided to us on websites, mobile sites, mobile applications, and other digital services and products controlled by **Sea-Bird Scientific,** 13431 NE 20th Street, Bellevue, Washington 98005  USA, that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, "Sea-Bird Sites"). Sea-Bird is the data controller for the processing of Personal Data under applicable law.

This Privacy Notice does not apply to Sea-Bird Sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy or to third-party Web sites to which Sea-Bird Sites may link.

**Types of Information We Collect Online**

The types of Personal Data that we may collect while you use the Sea-Bird Sites are described in this section and include both information that you provide to us and information that we collect automatically when you use the Sea-Bird Sites.  
For purposes of this Privacy Notice, "Personal Data" means information that identifies you or that could reasonably be used to identify you. Examples of Personal Data include name, address, telephone number, and email address.

**Information You Provide**

You do not have to register for a service or program to receive much of the information available through Sea-Bird Sites. However, some of our content is available only to registered or identified users and will require you to set up a profile or provide specific information about yourself in order to provide you the service.

**Personal Data You Provide When Visiting Sea-Bird Sites**  
Sea-Bird collects Personal Data that you provide on Sea-Bird Sites, for example, when purchasing a product, to receive marketing products and information, contact Sea-Bird customer service, or respond to Sea-Bird questionnaires or surveys. This could include:

  * Contact Information such as your name, address, phone number, or email address
  * Registration Information such as your username and password
  * Remuneration information when you provide a service to Sea-Bird in your capacity as a healthcare professional
  * Employment, education and other background information when you inquire about employment with Sea-Bird
  * Payment information (such as banking information, payment card number, expiration date, delivery address, and billing address)
  * Content you may provide (for example, when you complete our Online Contact Form or submit other information).

**Personal Data You Share During Other Interactions with Sea-Bird**  
You may contact Sea-Bird to ask questions, discuss your concerns, or report issues regarding our products. If you communicate with or request information from Sea-Bird, you may be prompted to provide your contact information as well as any Personal Data that is relevant to your request.

**Information That May Be Collected Automatically**  
When you use the Sea-Bird Sites, we also may collect certain usage and device information automatically as described below.

**IP Address**  
We may record the Internet Protocol ("IP") address of your computer or other electronic device when you visit the Sea-Bird Sites. An IP address identifies the electronic device you use to access the Sites, which allows us to maintain communication with your computer as you move about Sea-Bird Sites and to customize content.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**  
We also collect information about your use of Sea-Bird Sites through tracking technologies such as cookies and web beacons. A "cookie" is a unique numeric code that is transferred to your computer to track your interests and preferences and to recognize you as a return visitor. A "Web beacon" is a transparent graphic image placed on a Web site, e-mail or advertisement that enables the monitoring of things such as user activity and site traffic. These technologies help remember your preferences and allow us to bring you the content and features that are likely to be of greatest interest to you on the basis of "clickstream" data that shows your previous activities on Sea-Bird Sites.

We utilize Google Display Advertising (such as Retargeting with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, DoubleClick Campaign Manager integration, and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting) to (1) show you our ads on other websites based on your prior visits to Sea-Bird Sites, and (2) better understand our ad impressions and use of ad services. In connection with the Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting service, we may use data from Google's interest-based advertising or third-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) with Google Analytics to understand and improve our marketing campaigns and Site content.

Some of our online advertising takes place through Google Display Advertising. As part of this program, we use Google Analytics features such as Retargeting. In connection with that feature and others offered by ad networks, we and the operators of ad networks, including Google, may use third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) - and in some cases first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) - to inform, optimize and serve ads across the Internet, based on a user's past visits to Sea-Bird Sites. We also may show you ads from some of our affiliated companies when you visit Sea-Bird Sites.

You can opt out of Google Ads by visiting <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences>. If you do not want your data used by Google Analytics, you can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on at the Google Analytics opt-out page.

This Sea-Bird Site is not designed to respond to "do not track" signals received from browsers.

To learn more about cookies and other tracking technologies, including how to disable them, please visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. Please note that some cookies are essential to the functioning of our Sites and deleting or disabling them will reduce the site's functionality.

**Mobile Tracking**  
Some Sea-Bird Sites are available either as mobile applications or mobile sites that you can use on your mobile device. If you use a mobile device to access and use the Sea-Bird Sites, we may collect the following mobile-specific information in addition to the other information described above: device or advertising ID, device type, hardware type, media access control ("MAC") address, international mobile equipment identity ("IMEI"), the version of your mobile operating system, the platform used to access or download the Sea-Bird Site (e.g., Apple, Google, Amazon, Windows), location information and usage information about your device and your use of the Sea-Bird Sites.

**Information Collected from Other Sources**  
We may combine information about you from a visit to one Sea-Bird Site with information about you from visits to other Sea-Bird Sites. We may also combine information about you that is collected through the Sea-Bird Sites with information that we have collected offline, as well as with information provided to us by third parties, such as third-party list providers.

**How We Use Your Information**  
We use your Personal Data to provide you the product and services you request, communicate with you, improve your experience on the Sea-Bird Sites, generally improve our products and services and for other internal business purposes. These uses may also include the recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction of Personal Data. The Personal Data we collect about you may be stored for five years following the most recent interaction we have had with you, after which point it will be archived only for so long as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out above, in accordance with applicable laws.

**Providing Product and Services You Request**  
If you choose to purchase a product or receive our services, we use the Personal Data that you provide through Sea-Bird Sites to manage your orders and invoices, to process payments, to respond to your questions, provide you the services you request and offer an optimal customer experience.

**Marketing**  
You may also receive marketing information from Sea-Bird and related affiliates, such as offers regarding Sea-Bird related products or services, invitations to participate in surveys about our products, or notifications about special promotions. In such cases, we will use your contact and other Personal Data to send you marketing information.

**Customized User Experiences**  
The Personal Data that you provide may be used to create customized offers, information, or services tailored to your interests and preferences. Also, we may use your IP address and the data that we obtain automatically through the use of cookies or similar tracking technologies to make our Sea-Bird Sites easier to use and navigate as well as to personalize the content provided on Sea-Bird Sites by anticipating the information and services that may be of interest to you.

**Business and Product Improvement**  
In order to discover new facts that could help Sea-Bird better understand customer needs and help improve, develop, and evaluate product, services, materials, and programs. Sea-Bird analyzes the information that you have provided. For these purposes Sea-Bird does not use information that can directly identify you.

**Site Analytics and Improvement**  
We may use the information that you provide and the information we collect automatically about your use of the Sea-Bird Sites to monitor user traffic patterns and preferences for site improvement, analytics and optimization.

**Legal Basis for Processing**  
Under European data protection laws, Sea-Bird must have a legal basis to process your Personal Data. The legal basis that applies in a instance will depend on for which of the specific purposes described above Sea-Bird is processing your Personal Data:

  * In certain cases, Sea-Bird may ask for your consent to collect and process your Personal Data. Should you choose to provide your consent, you may later withdraw your consent by contacting us as described in the "Your Privacy Choices" section. Please note that the withdrawal of consent will not affect processing which has already occurred.
  * In other instances, the processing of your Personal Data may be necessary in order to comply with an applicable law or regulation or for the performance of a contract to which you are subject. You may not be able to opt-out of this processing, or your choice to opt-out may impact our ability to perform a contractual obligation otherwise owed to you.
  * In still other instances, Sea-Bird may process your Personal Data based on Sea-Bird's legitimate interests in communicating with you about our products and services, and about scientific research and educational opportunities. You have the right to opt-out of all such processing of your Personal Data. You may do so by contacting us as described in the "Your Privacy Choices" section.

**Information We Share**  
We only share your Personal Data with third parties as described below. We do not sell or rent Personal Data to third parties for their own marketing purposes.

**Third-Party Advertising and Online Behavioral Advertising**  
You may be provided with online advertisements of Sea-Bird products and services on third-party websites and mobile services that are tailored to you, for example, on the basis of information that you provide to Sea-Bird or a third-party website you are visiting, or of your browsing activity, purchases, or interests. These types of tailored online advertisements may come through several sources, such as the following:

  * We may share with our advertising service providers your non-identifying information that we have obtained from cookies and other tracking technologies on our Sea-Bird Sites.
  * Some Sea-Bird Sites participate in online behavioral advertising (this is also sometimes called re-target advertising or interest-based advertising). You can identify these sites by the "Advertising Choices" link in the footer. Our advertising network partners may place and use cookies on Sea-Bird Web sites and on other third-party Web sites to collect information about your activities in order to provide you with online advertisements that are based on your interests. When a Sea-Bird online behavioral advertisement is delivered to you, you will see an "Ad Choices" icon. Clicking on the icon or link will take you to a Web site where you can manage or opt out of the use of data about your browsing history that is used for the delivery of online behavioral advertisements. If you opt out, you may still see advertisements online, including advertisements from Sea-Bird that are based on other information (e.g., based on the content of the page being viewed rather than your prior clickstream activity). In some cases, data may still be collected about your browsing activity by these third-party advertisers, but they will not use this data to deliver advertisements that are based on your past online browsing behavior. You can also opt out now by clicking here.
  * Some Web browsers may transmit "do-not-track" signals to Web sites with which the browser communicates. As of the Effective Date of this Privacy Notice, an industry standard has not yet been established on how to respond to these signals. Therefore, Sea-Bird does not currently respond to these signals. As discussed above, you can opt-out from advertisers that use your browsing history to deliver online behavioral advertisements by visiting adchoices.

**Affiliates, Vendors and Suppliers**  
We have relationships with suppliers and affiliated companies, who help us operate our business and for whom it may be necessary to have access to your Personal Data in the course of providing services to Sea-Bird. We will not authorize these parties to use your Personal Data for any purpose that is not related to Sea-Bird and its related affiliates business operation, and we do not share Personal Data from countries that require consent, unless appropriate consent has been obtained in advance to sharing with related affiliates. We require them to handle your Personal Data collected in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

**Co-branded Sites**  
We may partner with other companies to provide you with content or services on a joint or "co-branded" basis. At a co branded site, you will see both the Sea-Bird logo and the logo of the co-branding partner displayed on your screen. You should read the individual privacy policies of our co-branding partners, as they may differ in some respects from ours. Reading these policies will help you to make an informed decision about whether to provide your information to a given site.

**Product Reports**  
If you contact Sea-Bird regarding your experience in using one of our products, we may use the information that you provide in submitting reports to the designated government regulatory authority, as required of us by law.

**Legal Rights and Obligations**  
In certain limited circumstances, Sea-Bird may need to disclose your Personal Data in order to comply with a legal obligation or demand, such as to comply with reporting obligations to our governing regulatory authorities regarding the safety of our products, or in connection with the sale or transfer of one of our product lines or divisions, which includes the services provided through one or more of the Sea-Bird Sites. In such instances, we will take measures to protect your Personal Data to the extent possible. We also reserve the right to use Personal Data to investigate and prosecute users who violate our rules or who engage in behavior that is illegal or harmful to others or to others' property.

**Change in Organization**  
In the event Sea-Bird decides to reorganize or divest our business through sale, merger, or acquisition, Sea-Bird may share Personal Data about you with actual or prospective purchasers. We will require any actual or prospective purchasers to treat this Personal Data in a manner consistent with this notice.

**Children Privacy**  
Sea-Bird does not knowingly collect or use any Personal Data directly from children on Sea-Bird Sites (Danaher defines as "children" as minors younger than 18). We do not knowingly allow children to order our products, to communicate with us, or to use any of our online services. If you are a parent and become aware that your child has provided us with information, please contact us using one of the methods specified below, and we will work with you to address this issue.

**Your Privacy Choices**  
You have the right to see and get a copy of Personal Data about you that we maintain as well as to ask us to make corrections to inaccurate or incomplete Personal Data about you. You may have the right to receive data you have provided to us in a machine-readable format and to transmit that data to another controller. You may also request the erasure of your Personal Data or the restriction of its processing, or object to the processing of Personal Data about you. To seek access to Personal Data about you, to file a concern, complaint, or request for correction, or to opt-out of particular programs, please contact our Privacy Office by clicking on the "Contact Us" link on the Sea-Bird Site you are using, by using the Sea-Bird contact information on the Sea-Bird mobile application you are using, or by emailing us at [news@seabird.com](mailto:news@seabird.com). You may also send a letter to the following address:

**Sea-Bird Scientific  
Attn: Privacy**  
13431 NE 20th Street,  
Bellevue, Washington  
98005  USA

The [Country] Data Protection Authority is responsible for making sure that privacy law is followed in [Country]. For more information about your privacy rights, or if you are not able to resolve a problem directly with us and wish to make a compliant, contact: [Sea-Bird.com.

In all communications to Sea-Bird, please include your email address, the Web site address, mobile application, and/or the specific Sea-Bird product to which you provided Personal Data (e.g., SeaBird.com), and a detailed explanation of your request. If you would like to delete, amend, or correct your Personal Data and are contacting us by email, please put "Deletion Request" or "Amendment/Correction Request" in the subject line of the email. We will respond to all reasonable requests in a timely manner and may need to further confirm your identity in order to process certain requests.

**Data Security**  
Sea-Bird maintains reasonable technical, administrative and physical controls to secure any Personal Data collected through the Sea-Bird Sites. However, there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party could intercept an Internet transmission, or that someone will find a way to thwart our security systems. We urge you to exercise caution when transmitting Personal Data over the Internet, especially your financial-related information. Sea-Bird cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not gain access to your Personal Data; therefore, when submitting Personal Data to Sea-Bird Sites, you must weigh both the benefits and the risks.

**Third Party Sites and Social Media Plug-ins**  
This Privacy Notice does not apply to Sea-Bird Sites that do not link to this Privacy Notice, or to third-party Web sites to which Sea-Bird Sites may link. Sea-Bird Sites may use social media plug-ins (e.g., the Facebook "Like" button, "Share to Twitter" button) to enable you to easily share information with others. When you visit Sea-Bird Sites, the operator of the social plug-in can place a cookie on your computer or other electronic device that enables that operator to recognize individuals who have previously visited our Site. If you are logged into the social media Web site (e.g., Facebook, Twitter) while browsing on our Sea-Bird Site, the social media plug-in allows that social media Web site to receive information that you have visited our Sea-Bird Site. The social media plug-in also allows the social media Web site to share information about your activities on our Sea-Bird Site with other users of their social media Web site. These sharing settings are managed by the social media Web site and governed by its privacy policy.

**Accessing Our Sites Globally**  
This site is owned and operated by Sea-Bird in the United States, but the information you provide will be accessible to our affiliates, vendors, and suppliers in other countries in accordance with this policy. Furthermore, if you are visiting this site from a country other than the United States, your communication with us will necessarily result in the transfer of information across international borders. The level of legal protection for Personal Data is not the same in all countries; however, we will take the security measures described in this Privacy Notice in an effort to keep your information secure. By using this site, you understand that your Personal Data will be stored and processed in the United States and in any country to which we may transfer your information in the course of our business operations.

**Notice to California Residents**  
Subject to certain limits under California Civil Code § 1798.83, California residents may ask us to provide them with (i) a list of certain categories of Personal Data that we have disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, and (ii) the identity of those third parties. To make this request, California residents may contact us at [news@seabird.com](mailto:news@seabird.com).

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**  
We will only use Personal Data in the manner described in this Privacy Policy in effect when the information was collected from you or as authorized by you. However, and subject to any applicable consent requirements, we reserve the right to change the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be reflected on this page with a new effective date. Sea-Bird encourages you to review this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes. Any Personal Data collected upon your continued use of Sea-Bird Sites will be handled in accordance with the currently-posted Privacy Policy.

## Additional Language for Online Terms of Use

**Privacy and Security**

Sea-Bird (Sea-Bird Scientific), along with its affiliates and subsidiaries respect your privacy, value our relationship, and are committed to safeguarding your privacy. We understand the importance of privacy to our customers and visitors to the Sea-Bird websites. Our use of Personal Data is governed by our Privacy Policy and by accessing and using the Sea-Bird websites, you agree to be bound by that Privacy Policy.

You recognize and agree that when submitting your personally identifiable information to Sea-Bird websites, while Sea-Bird has safeguards in place to prevent unauthorized access or interception, there is no absolute guarantee of security. IN THE UNLIKELY EVENT OF AN INTERCEPTION OR UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS DESPITE OUR EFFORTS, Sea-Bird SHALL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE FOR SUCH INTERCEPTIONS OR UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS, OR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING LOST PROFITS) SUFFERED BY A CUSTOMER OR USER, EVEN IF Sea-Bird HAS PREVIOUSLY BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES, Sea-Bird DOES NOT WARRANT, EITHER EXPRESSLY OR IMPLIED, THAT THE INFORMATION PROVIDED BY ANY CUSTOMER SHALL BE FREE FROM INTERCEPTION OR UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS, AND DOES NOT PROVIDE ANY IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. EACH CUSTOMER IS RESPONSIBLE FOR MAINTAINING THE CONFIDENTIALITY OF HIS OR HER OWN PASSWORD.
